Guide to the Elizabeth Gurley Flynn Papers TAM.118
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
After her death in 1964, the papers of Elizabeth Gurley Flynn were held by her estate, and eventually transferred to the custody of the Communist Party, USA. In 1983 a portion of the papers was donated to the Tamiment Library at New York University. These papers were, for the most part, concerned with Flynn's activities in the Communist Party, 1937-1964. In 1984 a second donation was made; this body of documents and papers from Flynn's earlier years and included the papers of her son, Fred Flynn. The Library was also given several batches of documents collected by historians Rosalyn Baxandall and Helen C. Camp Files obtained under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). The accession number associated with this gift is 1986.044. At a later date, one manuscript box of material was apparently received from the Reference Center for Marxist Studies Library (located in the headquarters of the Communist Party USA), and this comprises the last box of the collection. A button discovered in the repository was added to the collection in 2014. The accession number associated with this item is 2014.087.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Communist Party, USA in 1983; an additional accession was donated by Rosalyn Baxandall in 1984. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1964.001, 1986.044, and 2014.087.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
This collection, with the exception of Series IX: Boxes 13 & 14, and Series X, is available on microfilm (Film R-7263) for use in this repository only. Researchers must use microfilm for this collection, except for what is listed above.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Elizabeth Gurley Flynn Photographs (PHOTOS 018)
Elizabeth Gurley Flynn: Joe Hill Case Materials (TAM 529)
Elizabeth Gurley Flynn: Peter Martin and Roberta Bobba Materials (TAM 348)
Scope and Content Note
The Elizabeth Gurley Flynn Papers, Microfilm Edition, contains correspondence, biographical sketches, autobiographical notes, telegrams, published and unpublished articles, speeches and poems, diaries, itineraries, clippings, programs, invitations, course materials, documents pertaining to legal proceedings and files produced by various government agencies. Printed materials are also included, among them election campaign literature, broadsides, handbills and posters, annotated books, pamphlets and articles, clippings, galley proofs for The Alderson Story, and several copies of sheet music for "The Rebel Girl" by Joe Hill, including a copy in Russian.
Throughout her life Flynn kept scrapbooks. The earliest contain newspaper accounts of her speeches. Later ones include her traveling schedules and more detailed evidence of her activities including handbills, invitations and programs to events at which she was a featured speaker, or which she attended on behalf of the CPUSA.
From time to time Flynn made autobiographical notes with the intention of organizing a second volume to follow The Rebel Girl, which covers her life story only up to 1926. These autobiographical notes, summarizing important phases of her life history, have been placed chronologically throughout the collection as she wrote them.
Notable correspondents in represented in the collection include: John Abt, Herbert Aptheker, Roger Baldwin, Ella Reeve Bloor, Benjamin Davis, Eugene V. Debs, Eugene Dennis, Marguerite DeSilver, Mary Dreier, Joseph Ettor, Marie Equi, William Z. Foster, Arturo Giovanitti, Mike Gold, Emma Goldman, Alice Hamilton, William D. Haywood, John Haynes Holmes, Claudia Jones, Helen Keller, Vito Marcantonio, Robert Minor, Tom Moody, and Art Young.
Separated Material
Photographs were removed and placed into the Elizabeth Gurley Flynn Photographs (PHOTOS 018).
Two pennants were separated and placed in the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives General Archives and Ephemera Collection.
Sacco-Vanzetti Trial, Dedham, Mass., 1921.; Political crimes and offenses |z United States.; Feminists -- United States.; Manuscripts for publication.; Communism -- United States.; Programs (documents); handbills; New York (N.Y.).; Communist trials -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Poetry.; Photographic prints.; Correspondence.; Civil rights -- United States.; Women and socialism -- United States.; Scrapbooks.; Speeches.; American Civil Liberties Union; Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley; Abt, John J.; Aptheker, Herbert, 1915-2003.; Giovannitti, Arturo M., 1884-1959; Baxandall, Rosalyn Fraad, 1939-; Davis, Benjamin J. (Benjamin Jefferson), 1903-1964; Young, Art, 1866-1943.; Tresca, Carlo, 1879-1943; Minor, Robert, 1884-1952; Mooney, Thomas J., 1882-1942; Keller, Helen, 1880-1968.; Gold, Michael, 1893-1967; Marcantonio, Vito, 1902-1954; Ettor, Joseph J.; Industrial Workers of the World; Jones, Claudia, 1915-1964.; Hill, Joe, 1879-1915; Hamilton, Alice; Haywood, Big Bill, 1869-1928; Holmes, John Haynes, 1879-1964; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Baldwin, Roger Nash, 1884-1981; France, Clarens; Foster, William Z., 1881-1961; Flynn, Katherine; Flynn, Fred, 1910-1940; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926; Equi, Marie; Dreier, Mary E. (Mary Elisabeth), 1875-1963; DeSilver, Marguerite; Communist Party of the United States of America; Bloor, Ella Reeve, 1862-1951
- Series I: Family and Early Life, 1890-1970
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains biographical materials about Flynn's parents and siblings in addition to her school records, early compositions, awards, clippings and three scrapbooks of poetry and literary personalities that interested her.
  - Father Thomas Flynn, news clippings, bio notes Reel 1, 1896-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - DW Clippings on Mother Reel 1, 1945, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Early compositions Reel 1, 1902-1906 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Old poetry scrapbooks Reel 1, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Prize winning essay Reel 1, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - School record/clippings Reel 1, 1903-1906 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook of clippings and poetry Reel 1, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II: The Rebel Girl and the IWW, 1907-1917
  Text from Flynn's speeches, early manuscripts, drafts for pamphlets, letters, datebooks, notes, clippings, posters and materials on the Lawrence and Paterson strikes documenting her activities with the IWW are contained here. Material on Joe Hill and some early correspondence are also included.
  - Early newspaper clippings Reel 1, 1906-1907 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Early newspaper clippings Reel 1, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Diary of inspirational poems Reel 1, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Evaluation of the Labor Leader Reel 1, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - MS--Problems of Organizing Women. Published in Solidarity. (Badly deteriorated) Reel 1, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - MS--Jungle Law, outline Reel 1, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Early speeches--Women and Socialism, Necessity of Deciding... Reel 2, 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, fragments of speeches, biographical? Reel 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Pamphlet--To the Coal Miners of District #6 UMW (New Lafferty Cases) Reel 2, 1909, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Course Outline--Birth of Cotton Industry Reel 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Notes for lecture--"Women in Modern Industry" Reel 2, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Note to EGF from Emma Goldmann, Dec 18 1910 Reel 2 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - MS--IWW and working women (Lawrence strike) Reel 2, [1912] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - MS--Story of my arrest and imprisonment, Spokane, 1910 Reel 2 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lawrence strike Reel 2, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Carlo Tresca's notes to EGF. Annotated copy of "Sonnets from the Portugese," ticket to Hobo Ball, NY, birth control ad, notes and reflctions on Tresca, 1939 and 1945. Reel 2, 1912, 1939, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Smith-Preston case: a refiew of the trial, 1915. Morris R. Preston, carbon Reel 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - MS on women in Socialist Party and IWW Reel 2, [1915] (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, IWW, Socialist Party. Deteriorating Reel 2, 1910-1929 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Recollections--IWW History Reel 2, [1915] (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - MS--Mexico, Outline Reel 2, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letter from E.V. Debs to EGF re Joe Hill, 8/20/15 Reel 2, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - MS--"On Birth Control" Reel 2, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - MS--Men on women Reel 2, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - IWW history Reel 2, 1915-1924 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - MS--Patriotism and Preparedness Reel 2, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - MS--On Women Reel 2, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Notes for speeches--On War, IWW Reel 2, 1917-1920 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - IWW clippings, fragile Reel 2, 1913-1920's (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Series III: Defense Activities, 1917-1927
  Correspondence, handbills, leaflets, telegrams, and posters having to do with Flynn's involvement in the Workers Defense Fund, Garland Fund, International Labor Defense and the American Civil Liberties Union form the larger part of this series. Materials from the Sacco and Vanzetti case are also included, as well as letters and telegrams from the 1926 testimonial dinner in her honor.
  - Misc. correspondence to EGF--Workers Defense Reel 2, 1917-1927 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Letters from Wm. Z. Foster Reel 2, 1919, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Der Kommunist, June 1920 Reel 2 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Notes on Fascism Reel 2, [1920] (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Notebook/review of TV Powderly's 30 Years of Labor Reel 2, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills, etc. Reel 2, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Clippings, broadsides, Socialist Party Reel 2, 1907-1922 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Page from The Labor Herald, July 1922 Reel 2 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Palmer Raids, Oakland, Ca Reel 2, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Labor Defense Council pamphlet Reel 2, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Political Persecution Today, 2 copies, International Labor Defense C'tee Reel 2, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - writings--"Radical Tales" Reel 3, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Clippings on Fascism Reel 3, 1920-1928 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Programs from EGF speaking engagements Reel 3, 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - NJ textile strike pamphlet Reel 3, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Passaic textile, poor condition Reel 3, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Passaic, misc Reel 3, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Scrapbook, souveniers from 20 yr. testimonial dinner, Sacco & Vanzetti letter, telegrams. 2/14/26 Reel 3, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - 2 programs from 20 yr. testimonial dinner Reel 3, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - 5 postcards advertising Flynn speaking engagements Reel 3, [1910, 1924], undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Speaking itinerary, clippings, notes--ILD Reel 3, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - ILD correspondence to EGF, pamphlets Reel 3, 1924-1936 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Pamphlet--Spies in Steel, by Frank L. Palmer Reel 3, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Labor Defender, May 1928 Reel 3 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Pamphlet--Eight Prisoners in the Kingston Cells, by Canadian Labor Defense League Reel 3, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Clippings--Labor Defender Reel 3, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Letter to EGF from John Haynes Holmes re Sacco & Vanzetti Defense Reel 3, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Miscellaneous material on Sacco & Vanzetti--clippings, notes, defense Reel 3, 1920-1959 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Sacco-Vanzetti clippings Reel 3, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - ILD clippings Reel 3, [1920]-1939 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Misc Ms. notes Reel 3, [1917]-1939 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - EGF on Sacco & Vanzetti, notes & MS Reel 3, [1920]-1941 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Series IV: Sojourn in the West, 1927-1936
  This series contains telegrams, correspondence, medical records and reports relating to Flynn's illness and recuperation. Flynn's first attempts at writing poetry are here in a small notebook.
  - Correspondence and papers c/o Marie Equi, EGF's stay in Oregon Reel 3, 1927-1937 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Series V: EGF's "Second Life", 1937-1952
  Flynn's activities form the largest series of her personal papers and are broken down into four subseries: A. ACLU Case, 1938-1940, Documents and clippings; B. Fred Flynn, 1910-1940, Papers and Correspondence; C. Tresca's Death, 1943, Mostly Clippings; D. CPUSA Activities, Scrapbooks, itineraries, drafts of speeches, notes and correspondence from "Life of the Party" (Flynn's Daily Worker column, notes from classes in Labor History taught at the Workers School, invitations and clippings relating to CP functions. This subseries also includes: Election campaigns on the Party ticket: Representative at Large, 1942, Congress, 1954, Manhattan City Council, 1957; and Trips to Europe: France, 1945, France and England, 1950.
  - General
    - Biographical, Flynn speaking itinerary for ILD Reel 3, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - 3 copies of Equal Justice, Journal of ILD Reel 3, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - List of articles and speeches Reel 4, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Certificate of literacy issued to EGF, SUNY Reel 4, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - MS--Recollections of Frame-Ups" for Masses & Mainstream. Fragile Reel 4, [1927, 1937] (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook--newspaper, handbills, etc. Reel 4, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Notebook of poetry and autobiographical notes, mostly poetry Reel 4, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Article in NM on coal mines Reel 4, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - programs for testimonial dinners EGF participated in Reel 4, 1936-1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - DW clippings, autobiographical or about family members Reel 4, 1930-1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Clipping, NY Times ad, protesting HR 2122 intro by J. Parnell Thomas, March Reel 4, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, DW on Lincoln Brigade, EGF addresses large group as CP member Reel 4, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Programs from mass protests Reel 4, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Speaking itinerary ILD, some dated, some undated Reel 4, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Poetry, drafts, notes, clippings Reel 4, 1938-1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Drafts for recruiting pamphlets CPUSA Reel 4, 1930-1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - I have no regrets--from Women Today Reel 4, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Scrapbook--newspaper, handbills etc Reel 4, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Text of radio speech, May Day, Pittsburgh Reel 4, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Outlines for classes on labor history taught at Workers' School NYC Reel 4, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Course notes from the Workers School Reel 4, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Women in American Socialist Struggles, data & MS copies Reel 4, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Invitation for EGF to speak at Labor Day celebrations Reel 4, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Statement re classes taught at Nat'l Training School Reel 4, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Course notes, American Labor History Reel 4, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Lecture notes, American Labor History Reel 4, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Class notes, American Labor History, Workers School, Nat'l Training School Reel 5, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Outlines for classes on American Labor History, Workers School Reel 5, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 26A)
    - Copies of protest letters from incident at Flynn speech, Adena Ohio, Oct 1938 Reel 5 (Box 2, Folder 26B)
    - Letter, Margaret De Silver re Carlo Tresca, Oct 1939 Reel 5 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Course Outline, the Workers School. IWW and its forerunners Reel 5, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Attacks on Labor and labor's rights ILD??, lists of prisoners, other cases Reel 5, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills, etc Reel 5, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills, etc Reel 5, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Personal correspondence cards Reel 5, 1931-1940 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Visitor Button (not microfilmed), 1939 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Biographical file, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Subseries A: ACLU Case, 1938-1940
    - ACLU pamphlets Reel 5, 1924-1925, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Report on the Dies committee, ACLU (copy) Reel 5, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Defense committee for Civil Rights for Communists Reel 5, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - ACLU case, Legal correspondence & copies (Feb-March, 1940) Reel 5 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Pamphlets and other printed materials from ACLU case Reel 5, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - ACLU case, EGF reply to charges at Board mtg, 3 copies, March 4, 1940 Reel 5 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Reprints of 2 articles--New Masses 3/19/40 and DW 3/17/40, protesting ACLU ouster Reel 5 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Conference on civil rights, April 10, 1940 Reel 5 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence protesting ouster of EGF from ACLU, response to article in Reel 5, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 41-42)
    - ACLU, correspondence Corliss LaMont/EGF, May 1940 Reel 5 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence and copies, ACLU case, Rev. J.H. Holmes, R. Baldwin, Reel 5, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Minutes of extraordinary meeting, May 7, 1940, ACLU Reel 5 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - ACLU, EGF's notes. Feb-May Reel 6, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - ACLU, other correspondence to EGF Reel 6, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - ACLU, press releases, minutes, bulletins to membership Reel 6, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence and working copy of summary of meeting, 5/7/40 Reel 6, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Communists and Civil Liberties Survey Graphic, May Reel 6, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - ACLU meeting summary, May 7, 1940 Reel 6 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Press releases from EGF re ACLU, May 1940 Reel 6 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - ACLU, EGF copies and correspondence with Board, May 1939-June 1940 Reel 6, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Bylaws and Board of Directors, ACLU Reel 6, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - EGF correspondence, ACLU case, returns from national Committee Reel 6, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - MS--critical of ACLU, found among papers, and report on prosecutions Reel 6, [1940] (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - ACLU carbon of proposed statement by Board Reel 6, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Clippings, ACLU Reel 6, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Clippings, ACLU, Flynn case Reel 6, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Subseries B: Fred Flynn, 1910-40
    - Fred Flynn, school composition Reel 6, 1920-1929 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Fred Flynn, papers, mementos Reel 6, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence on death of son, Fred Reel 6, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Poetry after Fred's death Reel 6, [1940] (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Fred Flynn, mementos Reel 6, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Subseries C: Tresca's Death, 1943
    - Clippings, death of Tresca Reel 6, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, Tresca murder, The Call, New Leader, bad condition, January 1943 Reel 6 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Clippings on Tresca, fragile, deteriorated and unprocessed Reel 6, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Pamphlets, clippings on Tresca, Tresca Memorial Committee Reel 7, [1945] (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Subseries D: CPUSA Activities
    - Clippings, "They have just begun to fight" Monongahela railroad strike, historical contracts Reel 7, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook materials Reel 7, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, June-July Reel 7, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Statement of Committee on Election Rights, National Federation for Constitutional Liberties Reel 7, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Clipping re Dill Pickle Club, founded by Jack Jones Reel 7, [1940-1949] (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills, etc Reel 7, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Letter to EGF from Helen Keller Reel 7, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Honorable withdrawal from American Newspaper Guild Reel 7, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills Reel 7, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - MS, a history of the IWW Reel 7, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Obituary, Art Young, Dec 31, 1943 Reel 7 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - CP history, consitutions of the CPU, marked for change by EGF Reel 7, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Vandenburg Speech, notes on the NY Times article by EGF Reel 7, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Notes on destruction of Fascism Reel 7, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Proof of legal advertisement, notice of dissolution of the Defense Committeefor Civil Rights of Communists, January 10, 1944 Reel 7 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills etc Reel 7, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Pages from diary, "Notes on People" Reel 7, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, misc Reel 7, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills etc Reel 7, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Autobiographical notes for period, 1919-46 Reel 7 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Notes on Homestead Strike and clipping by R. Baldwin Reel 7, [1946] (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills etc Reel 7, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Biographical sketch--Press release? 12/10/46 Reel 7, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - MS on Mother Bloor, pamphlet on Bloor Reel 7, 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - MS reviewing CPUS history Reel 7, 1940-1949, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Texts of radio speeches, on behalf of CPUSA candidates Reel 7, 1944-1950 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Excerpts from books or articles mentioning EGF and IWW Reel 7, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Autobiographical notes on trips Reel 7, 1940-1959 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Notebook of autobiographical events, diary? Reel 7, 1937-1948 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - MS--A Trade Unionist Should be a Communist Reel 7, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Notes on Public Speaking. Pamphlets on defense activities, notes Reel 8, 1942-1949 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Scrapbook--1944, 1945, 1946, 1947, Part I Reel 8 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Scrapbook--1944, 1945, 1946, 1947, Part II Reel 8 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - DW Clippings, mostly historical Reel 8, 1946, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Pamphlets--Meet the Communists, Women's Place Reel 8, 1946, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - List of articles for 1947, handwritten Reel 8 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Fragments of the Miami News, 2/17/48 Reel 8, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Program and Text for speech, CPUSA 14th Nat'l Convention Reel 8, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Text of Program for CPUSA 14th Nat'l Convention, 8/2/48 Reel 8, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills etc Reel 8, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Personal account/date book, backdated 1925-27 Reel 8, 1948-1957 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills, etc Reel 8, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Statement opposing confirmation of Tom Clark as Associate Justice Reel 8, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Outline for autobiography Reel 8, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Statement by EGF against Supreme Court appointment Reel 8, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Subseries D-1: Election Campaigns on the Party Ticket
    - Election campaign, EGF for Representative-at Large Reel 8, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - EGF for Congress, clippings, invitation Reel 8, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook material--Bronx campaign Reel 8, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Publicity campaign for City Council Reel 8, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Speeces, campaign for City Council Reel 9, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Clippings used in campaign for City Council Reel 9, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook--newspapers, handbills Reel 9, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Radio script--women in the elections, press release and pamphlet Reel 9, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Subseries D-2: Trips to France
    - EGF's notes while attending International des Femmes in Frances, Nov-Jan Reel 9, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Souvenirs from France Reel 9, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 10)